// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Which test is conducted to locate the faults in U.G. cables?",
    //immg:"img1",
    answer: "Loop Test",
    options: [
      "Loop Test",
      "External growler Test",
      "Breakdown Voltage Test",
      "Insulation Resistance Test"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "What does the number 1.40 represent if a stranded conductor is designated as 7/1.40?",
    answer: "Diameter of each conductor",
    options: [
      "Area of cross section",
      "Radius of one conductor",
      "Diameter of all conductor", 
      "Diameter of each conductor"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "What is the size of the neutral core of a 90 sq mm 31/2 core U.G cable?",
    
    answer: "50 Sq mm",
    options: [
      "45 Sq mm",
      "50 Sq mm",
      "70 Sq mm",
      "90 Sq mm"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "What is the name of the tool as shown in the figure?",
    immg:"img4",
    answer: "Crimping tool",
    options: [
      "cutting plier",
      "Wire stripper",
      "Crimping tool",
      "Side cutting plier"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which type of joint is used in over head lines for high tensile strength?",
    answer: "Western union joint",
    options: [
      "Scarfed joint",
      "Married Joint",
      "Western union joint",
      "Rat tail joint"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "What is the unit for quantity of electricity?",
    answer: "Coulomb",
    options: [
      "Mho",
      "Coulomb",
      "Volt/second",
      "Ampere/second"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "What is the name of the soldering method as shown in the figure? ",
    immg:"img7",
    answer: "Soldering gun",
    options: [
      "Dip Soldering",
      "Soldering iron",
      "Soldering gun",
      "soldering with flame"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "What is the name of the soldering method as shown in the figure?",
    immg:"img8",
    answer: "Temperature controlled soldering",
    options: [
      "Dip Soldering",
      "Soldering with blow lamp",
      "Soldering with soldering gun",
      "Temperature controlled soldering"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 9,
    question: "How many electrons are there in the third shell of the copper atom?",
    
    answer: "18",
    //immg:"img9",
    options: [
      "8",
      "13",
      "18",
      "29"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 10,
    question: "What is the formula for the Quantity of electricity (Q)?",
    //immg:"img10",
    answer: "Current x Time",
    options: [
      "Current x Time",
      "Voltage x Current",
      "Current x Resistance",
      "Voltage x Resistance"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 11,
    question: "Which formula is used to calculate the power of a DC circuit?",
    //immg:"img11",
    answer: "Current x voltage",
    options: [
      "Voltage x time",
      "Current x voltage",
      "Current x resistance",
      "Voltage x resistance"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 12,
    question: "What is the advantage of the stranded conductor over the solid conductor?",
    
    answer: "More flexible",
    options: [
      "cost is less",
      "More flexible",
      "less voltage drop",
      "more insulation resistance"
    ]
  },
 {
    numb: 13,
    question: "What is the advantage of the crimping terminations?",
    //immg:"img13",
    answer: "Avoid loose connections",
    options: [
      "Increase the voltage",
      "Reduce the load current",
      "Avoid loose connections",
      "Easy to replace"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 14,
    question: "Which part of the underground cable is protecting the metallic sheath against corrosion?",
    
    answer: "Bedding",
     //immg:"img14",
    options: [
      "Serving",
      "Bedding",
      "Armouring",
      "Lead Sheath"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 15,
    question: "What is the use of dipsoldering method?",
    // immg:"img15",
    answer: "Soldering miniature components on PCB",
    options: [
      "Hard soldering",
      "Piping and cable soldering work",
      "Soldering miniature components on PCB",
     "soldering of tin sheets"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 16,
    question: "Which is the semiconductor material?",
    
    answer: "Germanium",
    options: [
      "Eureka",
      "Ebonite",
      "Maganin",
      "Germanium"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 17,
    question: "What is the reading of the micrometer as shown in the figure?",
      immg:"img17",
    answer: "4.55mm",
    options: [
      "5.05mm",
      "5.00mm",
      "4.55mm",
      "4.05mm"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 18,
    question: "Which is used to measure the size of the conductor?",
      //immg:"img18",
    answer:"Standard wire gauge",
    options: [
      "Bevel gauge",
      "Vernier caliper",
      "Standard wire gauge",
      "Depth gauge"
    ]
  },
       {
    numb: 19,
    question: "What is the purpose of ‘serving’ layer in underground cable?",
    
    answer:"Protect armouring from atmospheric condition",
    options: [
      "Protect the cable from mechanical vibration",
      "Protect the cable from mechanical injury",
      "Protect metallic sheath against corrosion",
      "Protect armouring from atmospheric condition"
    ]
  },
        {
    numb: 20,
    question: "Which type of joint is used for extending the length of conductor in over head lines?",
   
    answer:"Western Union joint",
    options: [
      "Scarfed joint",
      "Aerial tap joint",
      "Britannia T joint",
      "Western Union joint"
    ]
  },  
    
             {
    numb: 21,
    question: "What is starving in extinguishing of fire?",
    
    answer:"Removing fuel element from the fire",
    options: [
      "Adding fue to the fire",
      "Using water to cool the fire ",
      "Removing fuel element from the fire",
      "Preventing oxygen supply to the fire"
    ]
  },
                 
        {
    numb: 22,
    question: "Which artificial respiration method is to be performed to the victim with injuries on the chest and belly?",
    
    answer:"Mouth to mouth method",
    options: [
      "Schafers method",
      "Mouth to mouth method",
      "Holger Nelson back pressure method",
      "Nelson arm lift back pressure method"
    ]
  },  
     {
    numb: 23,
    question: "Which type of occupational health hazard is cause for infection due to bacteria?",
    
    answer:"Biological hazard",
    options: [
      "Electrical Hazard",
      "Physiological hazard",
      "Biological hazard",
      "Pschological hazard"
    ]
  }, 
     {
    numb: 24,
    question: "Which is the golden hour for the victim injured on head with risk of dying?",
    
    answer: "First 30 minutes",
    options: [
      "First 15 minutes",
      "First 30 minutes",
      "First 45 minutes",
     "First 60 minutes"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 25,
    question: "Which condition of the victim is referred as COMA stage?",
    
    answer: "Lie totally senseless and do not respond to calls",
    options: [
      "Un consscious but can respond to calls",
      "Consicous but cannot resopnd to call",
      "Breathing and respond to call",
     "Lie totally senseless and do not respond to calls"
    ]
  },        
               {
    numb: 26,
    question: "Which criteria must be satisfied for the quality of PPE s?",
    
    answer:"It should with stand the hazards",
    options: [
      "It should with stand the hazards",
      "It cannot be used for long period",
      "made by non standard material",
      "low cost"
    ]
  }, 
     {
    numb: 27,
    question: "What is the possible range to measure the size of the wire in a Standard Wire Gauge(SWG)?",
    
    answer: "0-36",
    options: [
      "0-44",
      "0-42",
      "0-38",
     "0-36"
    ]
  },
          {
    numb: 28,
    question: "What is the name of the wire joint as shown in the figure?",
    immg:"img28",
    answer: "Knotted tap joint",
    options: [
      "Aerial tap joint",
      "Knotted tap joint",
      "Duplex cross tap joint",
     "Double cross tap joint"
    ]
  },

      {
    numb: 29,
    question: "What is the full form of XLPE Cable?",
    
    answer: "Cross Linked Poly Ethylene",
    options: [
      "Cross Line Poly Ethylene",
      "X ess Line Phase Earthing",
      "Cross Linked Poly Ethylene",
     "Excess Length Paper and Ebonite"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 30,
    question: "How many electrons are there in the valence shell of a copper atom?",
    
    answer: "1",
    options: [
      "1",
      "2",
      "8",
     "18"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 31,
    question: "Which effect of the electric current takes place in the neon lamp?",
    
    answer: "Gas ionization effect",
    options: [
      "Heating effect",
      "Magnetic effect",
      "Chemical effect",
     "Gas ionization effect"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 32,
    question: "What is the unit of insulation resistance?",
    
    answer: "Mega ohm",
    options: [
      "Ohm",
      "Kilo ohm",
      "Milli Ohm",
     "Mega ohm"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 33,
    question: "Which type of soldering flux is used for soldering aluminium conductors?",
    
    answer: "Kynal flux",
    options: [
      "Tallow",
      "Kynal flux",
      "Zinc Chloride",
     "Sal ammonia"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 34,
    question: "What is the name of the part marked X in UG cables as shown in the figure?",
    
    answer: "Lead sheath",
    immg:"img34",
    options: [
      "Serving",
      "Bedding",
      "Armouring",
     "Lead sheath"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 35,
    question: "What is the name of the joint as shown in the figure?",
    
    answer: "Married joint",
    immg:"img35",
    options: [
      "Married joint",
      "Scarfed Joint",
      "Western Union Joint",
     "Britannia Sraight Joint"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 36,
    question: "What is the use of Britannia T joint?",
    
    answer: "Tapping the service connection from overhead lines",
    
    options: [
      "Extending the length of the lines",
      "Inside and outside wiring installation",
      "Mechanical stress not required on conductor",
     "Tapping the service connection from overhead lines"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 37,
    question: "What is the name of the part marked X of the belted U.G cable as shown in the figure?",
    
    answer: "Lead sheath",
    immg:"img37",
    options: [
      "Jute filling",
      "Armouring",
      "Lead sheath",
     "Paper insulation"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 38,
    question: "What is the purpose of the bedding insulation in the U.G. cable?",
    
    answer: "Protect the metallic sheath against corrosion",
 
    options: [
      "Protect the cable fromn mechanical injury",
      "Protect the cable from moisture and gases",
      "Protect armouring from atomspheric condition",
     "Protect the metallic sheath against corrosion"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 39,
    question: "What are the two classifications of system of units?",
    
    answer: "Fundamental and derived",
 
    options: [
      "British and Metric",
      "Gravitational and non gravitational",
      "Fundamental and derived",
     "Metric and International"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 40,
    question: "What are fundamental units?",
    
    answer: "Length, Mass, Time",
 
    options: [
      "Length, Mass, Volume",
      "Length, Mass, Time",
      "Length, Mass, Area",
     "Length, Pressure, Volume"
    ]
  },
       {
    numb: 41,
    question: "What denotes letter ' in MKS system?",
    
    answer: "Meter",
 
    options: [
      "Mile",
      "Milli Meter",
      "Meter",
     "Micron"
    ]
  },

       {
    numb: 42,
    question: "How many millimetres are there in 1 inch?",
    
    answer: "25.4mm",
 
    options: [
      "2.54mm",
      "25.4mm",
      "24.5mm",
     "2.45mm"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 43,
    question: "Convert decimal 0.000659 to fraction?",
    
    answer: "659/1000000",
 
    options: [
      "659/10000",
      "659/100000",
      "659/1000000",
     "659/1000"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 44,
    question: "What is the square root of 529?",
    
    answer: "23",
 
    options: [
      "13",
      "23",
      "33",
     "43"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 45,
    question: "Identify the conventional symbol of material?",
    immg:"img45",
    answer: "Water",
 
    options: [
      "Water",
      "Concrete",
      "Asbestos",
     "Glass"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 46,
    question: "Identify the conventional symbol of material?",
    immg:"img46",
    answer: "Wood",
 
    options: [
      "Lead",
      "Glass",
      "Wood",
     "Paper"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 47,
    question: "Identify the name of instrument?",
    immg:"img47",
    answer: "Protractor",
 
    options: [
      "Set Square",
      "Protractor",
      "French curve",
     "T Square"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 48,
    question: "Identify the name of set square?",
    immg:"img48",
    answer: "45o set square",
 
    options: [
      "15o Set Square",
      "60o set square",
      "30o set square",
     "45o set square"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 49,
    question: "Compass used to draw for___.",
    
    answer: "circle",
 
    options: [
      "rectangle",
      "square",
      "circle",
     "triangle"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 50,
    question: "a+b = 15, a-b=10 Then 4ab=? ",
    
    answer: "125",
 
    options: [
      "125",
      "100",
      "120",
     "135"
    ]
  },
  // you can uncomment the below codes and make duplicate as more as you want to add question
  // but remember you need to give the numb value serialize like 1,2,3,5,6,7,8,9.....

  //   {
  //   numb: 6,
  //   question: "Your Question is Here",
  //   answer: "Correct answer of the question is here",
  //   options: [
  //     "Option 1",
  //     "option 2",
  //     "option 3",
  //     "option 4"
  //   ]
  // },
];
